AL MUMEETU SAIKAT

Phone: +88 01722301927, E-Mail: almumeetu@gmail.com, Naogaon, Bangladesh.

GitHub Portfolio Upwork LinkedIn W3schools

Summary

Since 2022, I've specialized in website design and development, prioritizing user-friendly experiences, eye-catching designs, responsiveness across devices, SEO-friendly content structures, and performance optimization for high-speed websites.

Skills

Web Design: HTML/HTML5, CSS/CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap, JavaScript jQuery, JSON and Ajax.

CMS: WordPress/WooCommerce (Basic)
Programming: PHP (Basic), JavaScript

Tools: Git, GitHub.

Experience

WebDev Software Solutions, Joypurhat (Web Designer)

Nov 2022 - Present

- Learned new materials, processes, and programs quickly.
- Attended training courses to build understanding of processes, techniques, and industry.
- Supported departmental tasks to increase understanding of industry processes.
- Established lasting relationships with peers, leadership and customers using strong communication and interpersonal skills.
- Learn Basic PHP and WordPress.

Upwork.com (Web Designer)

Jan 2023- Present

- Coded websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP and jQuery languages.
- Provided front-end website development using WordPress and other editing software.
- Upwork is a global freelancing platform where businesses and independent professionals connect and collaborate remotely.
- Upwork Profile Link: Al Mumeetu Saikat

Bdevs, Dhaka (Web Designer Intern)

Aug 2022 - Oct 2022

- Worked closely with developers on creating new code.
- Took detailed notes during team meetings and disseminated them to staff members.
- $\mbox{\sc Prioritized}$ and $\mbox{\sc problem-solved}$ several tasks concurrently with minimum supervision.
- Developed user interfaces with modern JavaScript frameworks, HTML5, and CSS3.
- Learn Responsive Web Design And SEO.
- Learn Bootstrap, SCSS And Basic Java Scripts.
- Learn PSD To HTML/HTML5/CSS/CSS3.

- Passionate about crafting seamless user experiences, I'm eager to learn and grow as a Web Design Trainee, bringing fresh perspectives to create visually stunning and intuitive websites.
- With a foundation in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, I'm excited to apply my skills in a dynamic team, contributing to innovative web projects and honing my design prowess.
- As a Web Design Trainee, I'm committed to staying abreast of the latest industry trends and technologies, striving to transform concepts into captivating, user-centric digital experiences.

Education

- HSC in Science, Jahangirpur Govt. Collage, Mohadevpur, Naogaon

Dec 2019 - Dec 2021

- SSC in Science, Bagdob High School, Mohadevpur, Naogaon

Jan 2014 - Nov 2019

Online Course Aug 2022 – Oct 2022

- Web Designer Courses: BanglaDevs

- PSD to HTML: Bangla-devs

- SASS & Bootstrap: Bangla-devs

Language

- Fluent English and Bengali.

Interests

- Back-end Development, Full Stack Development, Coding, Senior Web Developer, Travelling.